Aditi Polkam

Full Stack Solidity Developer | Technical Writer

aditipolkam.me +91 8623800883 aditipolkam@gmail.com

PROFILE

3+ years of experience in coding and problem-solving. 1+ years of experience in web frontend development with technologies like React, and NextJs. Experience in working closely with blockchain and other web3-related technologies. Passionate about research and technical writing with rich and understandable content.

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>Technical Content Writer Intern – Wow Labz, Bangalore</u> (Proof of Work - https://www.social.li/blog/)

Sept 2022 – present

- Conduct extensive research on web3 projects and concepts to write content for blogs and social media of a metaverse startup.
- Writing technically rich and unplagiarized content that is easy to understand with detailed summaries and statistics.

<u>Frontend Developer Intern – CFT Labs, Jaipur</u>

Aug 2022 – Sept 2022

- Used React to design and develop responsive websites for clients.
- Developed interactive websites with smooth API integrations.

<u>Senior Programming Instructor – Oman Coding Academy, Muscat</u>

July 2021– May 2022

- Researched programming for kids and developed a study curriculum for students aged between 10-13.
- Conducted one-on-one coding classes for kids, and designed Instagram posts with user-friendly content.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Pune Chapter Co-Lead The Phoenix Guild
- 2. Mentor for Shardeum's Workshop to deploy a token

- 3. Student of the Year (Std. 10) 2017
- 4. Open Source Contributor Hacktoberfest 2022

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, Solidity, SQL **Web Development:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node, Express,

React, SvelteJS, NextJS

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, SQLite, MongoDB

App Development: Android using Java **Other:** Git, Github, Linux, Ethereum **Project Management:** JIRA, Notion, Trello

PUBLICATIONS

1. Managing Innovation and Entrepreneurship in the New Normal – Are Grass-roots Innovations the Key to Future Sustainability?

EMERGE Research Journal by Symbiosis College of Arts and Commerce (https://symbiosiscollege.edu.in/assets/pdf/Research%20Journal_Emerge.pdf)

2. Survey Paper on Blockchain-Based Crowd-sourcing Systems and automation of Question Paper Generation

International Journal of Advance Research and Innovative Ideas in Education (http://ijariie.com/FormDetails.aspx?MenuScriptId=217470)

PROJECTS

Ask On Chain – an anonymous question-answering system (https://ask-on-chain.vercel.app/) (https://github.com/aditipolkam/ask-on-chain)

• A project built using NextJS, Solidity and Polygon which lets you ask questions anonymously and get answers from whoever you want.

Buidl Domains – a domain name service on the blockchain (https://buidl-domains.vercel.app/) (https://github.com/aditipolkam/buidl-domains)

• Contract that provides a unique domain that resides on blockchain as a Non-Fungible Token (NFT).

Spotify Song Downloader - download songs from Spotify links - albums, playlists, artists, single tracks. (https://github.com/aditipolkam/spotify-downloader)

- Developed a utility using Python to download mp3 files of the required songs.
- Worked with Spotify API and packages like spotipy, eyed3, ffmpeg, pytube, and ytmusicapi

3-word Jumble - mint a limited collection of NFTs (https://github.com/aditipolkam/epic-nfts) (https://nft-starter-project.aditipolkam.repl.co/)

- Developed the frontend with React using its efficient features to improve user experience.
- Worked with the Ethereum Blockchain and wrote the smart contract in Solidity.
- Used OpenZeppelin ERC721 standard for NFTs and OpenSea testnet to display NFTs.

Initial Coin Offering (https://github.com/aditipolkam/initial-coin-offering) (https://initial-coin-offering-aditipolkam.vercel.app/)

- An initial coin offering exclusively for the owners of the NFT collection.
- Use of ERC720 standard for token creation.

EDUCATION

• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •				
Course	Board/University	Institution Name	Year Of Passing	Percentage/CGPA
Degree	Savitribai Phule Pune University	Dhole Patil College of Engineering, Pune	2023 (expected)	9.43 GPA
Diploma	Autonomous	Government Polytechnic, Pune	2020	89.80%
10 th (School)	SSC Board	Sardar Dastur Nosherwan Girls' High School	2017	95.20%

IMPORTANT PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aditipolkam/

Blog: https://aditipolkam.hashnode.dev/ Github: https://github.com/aditipolkam

Codechef: https://www.codechef.com/users/aditipolkam

OTHER DETAILS

Languages known: English, Hindi, and Marathi

Address: Pune, Maharashtra, India Hobbies: Basketball, Reading, Hiking, etc